The future belongs to the mad.
Mad Max: Fury Road is a action, adventure, science
fiction film directed by George Miller.
An apocalyptic story set in the furthest reaches of our planet, in a stark desert landscape where
humanity is broken, and most everyone is crazed fighting for the necessities of life.
Within this world exist two rebels on the run who
just might be able to restore order.
Max Rockatansky, played by Tom Hardy.
Imperator Furiosa, played by Charlize Theron.
Nux, played by Nicholas Hoult.
Immortan Joe, played by Hugh Keays-Byrne.
Slit, played by Josh Helman.
Rictus Erectus, played by Nathan Jones.
Mad Max: Fury Road is a 2015 Australian post-apocalyptic action film co-written, co-produced and directed by
George Miller, who collaborated with Brendan McCarthy and Nico Lathouris on the screenplay.
The fourth instalment in the Mad Max franchise, it was produced by Village Roadshow Pictures and Kennedy
Miller Mitchell, and distributed by Roadshow Entertainment in Australia and by Warner Bros.
Pictures internationally.
The film stars Tom Hardy and Charlize Theron, with Nicholas Hoult, Hugh Keays-Byrne, Rosie
Huntington-Whiteley, Riley Keough, Zoë Kravitz, Abbey Lee, and Courtney Eaton.
Set in a post-apocalyptic desert wasteland where petrol and water are scarce commodities, it follows Max Rockatansky (Hardy), who joins
forces with Imperator Furiosa (Theron) against warlord Immortan Joe (Keays-Byrne) and his army, leading to a lengthy road battle.
Miller came up with the idea for Mad Max: Fury Road in 1987, but the film spent
many years in development hell before pre-production began in 1998.
Attempts to shoot the film in the 2000s were delayed numerous times due to the September 11 attacks, the Iraq War, and
controversies surrounding star Mel Gibson, leading Miller to recast Gibson's role of Max Rockatansky.
Miller decided to pursue the film again in 2007 after the
release of his animated comedy film Happy Feet.
In 2009, Miller announced that filming would begin in early 2011.
Hardy was cast as Max in June 2010, with
production planned to begin that November.
Principal photography was delayed several more times
before it actually began in July 2012.
The film wrapped in December 2012, although
additional footage was shot in November 2013.
Mad Max: Fury Road premiered in Los Angeles on 7 May 2015,
and was released in Australia on 14 May.
The film grossed $380.4 million at the worldwide box office,
making it the highest-grossing Mad Max film.
It was nominated for ten awards at the 88th Academy Awards, winning six awards, and received numerous other accolades, including Best Film from the National Board of Review,
eight AACTA Awards from twelve nominations including Best Film and Best Direction and was also named one of the top ten films of 2015 by the American Film Institute.
It has also been called one of the greatest action films of all time.
A prequel comic book series was published by Vertigo from May to August 2015.
A prequel film, Furiosa: A Mad Max Saga, was released on 24 May
2024, with Miller returning as writer and director.
The film explores themes of rescue, future, australia, chase, dystopia.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.